Long ago he made a deal to save someone he loved.
Ghost Rider is a thriller, action, fantasy film directed by Mark Steven Johnson.
In order to save his dying father, young stunt cyclist Johnny Blaze sells his soul to
Mephistopheles and sadly parts from the pure-hearted Roxanne Simpson, the love of his life.
Years later, Johnny's path crosses again with Roxanne, now a go-getting reporter, and also with
Mephistopheles, who offers to release Johnny's soul if Johnny becomes the fabled, fiery 'Ghost Rider'.
Johnny Blaze / Ghost Rider, played by Nicolas Cage.
Roxanne Simpson, played by Eva Mendes.
Carter Slade / Phantom Rider, played by Sam Elliott.
Blackheart / Black King, played by Wes Bentley.
Mephistopheles / Mephisto, played by Peter Fonda.
Young Johnny Blaze, played by Matt Long.
Ghost Rider is a 2007 American superhero film written
and directed by Mark Steven Johnson.
Based on the Marvel Comics character of the same name, it was produced by Columbia Pictures in association with Marvel
Entertainment, Crystal Sky Pictures, and Relativity Media, and distributed by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film stars Nicolas Cage as the titular character, with Eva Mendes, Wes Bentley, Sam
Elliott, Donal Logue, Matt Long, and Peter Fonda in supporting roles.
The film follows Johnny Blaze, a motorcycle stuntman who sells his soul and
becomes the Ghost Rider, a bounty hunter of evil demons.
Ghost Rider was released on February 16, 2007, in the United States.
The film was met with negative reviews from critics and grossed
$228.7 million worldwide against a $110 million budget.
Ghost Rider was released on DVD, Blu-ray and UMD on June 12, 2007.
A sequel, titled Ghost Rider: Spirit of Vengeance, was released on
February 17, 2012, with Cage reprising his role.
The film explores themes of dying and death, religion and
supernatural, superhero, possession, devil's son.
The tone is intense.